To introduce you to RNNs in PyTorch,
在这道练习中
I've created a notebook that will show you how to do
我们将介绍 PyTorch 中的 RNN
simple time series prediction with an RNN.
以及如何使用 RNN 执行简单的时间序列预测
Specifically, we'll look at some data and see if we can create
我们将查看一些数据并创建一个 RNN
an RNN to accurately predict the next data point given a current data point,
它会根据当前给定数据点准确预测下个数据点
and this is really easiest to see in an example.
下面通过一个示例来讲解
So, let's get started.
我们开始吧
I'm importing our usual resources,
导入常用资源
and then I'm actually going to create some simple input and target training data.
然后创建一些简单的输入和目标训练数据
A classic example is to use a sine wave as input
经典示例是使用正弦波作为输入
because it has enough variance and shape to be an interesting task,
因为它的形状变化多样 是个比较有意思的任务
but it's also very predictable.
而且很好预测
So, I want to create a sample input and target sequence of data points of length 20,
我将创建一个示例输入和目标数据点序列 长为 20
which I specify here as sequence length.
在这里指定为 seq_length
Recall that RNNs are meant to work with sequential data,
RNN 用于处理序列数据
and so the sequence length is
序列长度是指
just the length of a sequence that it will look at as input.
输入的序列长度
Often, the sequence length will indicate the number of words in
通常 序列长度是指句子中的单词数量
a sentence or just some length of numerical data as is the case here.
或者数字数据的长度 例如此处
So, in these two lines,
在这两行
I'm just going to generate the start of
生成正弦波的起始部分
a sine wave in a range from zero to Pi time steps.
范围是从 0 到 π 时间步
At first, I'm going to create a number of points that sequence length 20 plus 1,
首先创建一些点 数量为序列长度 20 加一
then I'm going to reshape my sine wave data to give it one extra dimension,
然后变形正弦波数据
the input size, which is just going to be one.
为其添加一个维度 input_size 值为 1
Then, to create an input and target sequence of the length I want,
要创建所需长度的输入和目标序列
I'm going to say an input X is equal to all but the last point in data,
在这里指出输入 x 等于数据中的最后一个点之外的所有点
and the target Y is equal to all but the first point.
目标 y 等于第一个点之外的所有点
So, X and Y should contain 20 data points and have an input size of one.
x 和 y 应该包含 20 个数据点 并且输入大小是 1
Finally, I'm going to display this data using the same x-axis.
最后 使用相同的 x 轴显示此数据
You can see the input X is in red and the target Y is shifted over by one in blue.
输入 x 用红点表示 目标 y 用蓝点表示并且移动了一位
So, if we look at this point as an example at the same time step,
查看同一时间步的这两个点
Y is basically X shifted one time step in the future,
y 比 x 往前移动了一个时间步
and that's exactly what we want.
这正是我们想要的结果
So, now we have our training data and
创建好训练数据后
the next step is defining an RNN to learn from this data.
下一步是定义学习此数据的 RNN
We can define an RNN as usual,
我们可以照常定义 RNN
which is to say as a class using PyTorche's NN library.
也就是使用 PyTorch 的 nn 库定义为类
The syntax will look similar to how we've defined CNNs in the past.
语法和之前定义 CNN 的相似
Let's actually click on the RNN documentation to read
打开 RNN 文档
about the parameters that our recurrent layer takes in as input.
看看传入递归层的参数
So, here's the documentation for an RNN layer.
这是 RNN 层级的文档
We can see that this layer is responsible for
此层级负责根据输入
calculating a hidden state based on its inputs.
计算隐藏状态
Now, to define a layer like this,
要定义这样的层级
we have these parameters: an input size,
我们可以利用以下参数
a hidden size, a number of layers and a few other arguments.
输入大小 隐藏大小 层级数量及其他参数
The input size is just the number of input features,
输入大小表示输入特征的数量
and in our specific case we're going to have inputs that are 20 values
我们的输入大小是在一个输入大小特征中
in sequence and one in input size features.
有 20 个序列值
This is like when we thought about the depth of an input image when we made CNN's.
这与创建 CNN 时输入图像的深度相似
Next, we have a hidden size that defines how many
下个参数是隐藏大小
features the output of an RNN will have and its hidden state.
表示 RNN 的输出特征数量以及隐藏状态
We also have a number of layers,
然后是层级数量
which if it's greater than one,
如果大于 1
just means we're going to stack two RNNs on top of each other.
则表示我们将堆叠两个 RNN
Lastly, I want you to pay attention to this batch first parameter.
最后请注意这个 batch_first 参数
If it is true, that means the input and output tensors that we
如果它为 true 则表示我们提供的输入和输出张量
provide are going to have the batch size as the first dimension,
第一个维度大小将为 batch_size
which in most cases that we go through will be true.
大多数情况下它都设为 true
So, this is how you define an RNN layer,
这就是定义 RNN 层级的方式
and later in the forward function we'll see that it takes
之后在 forward 函数中
in an input and an initial hidden state,
它会接受输入和初始隐藏状态
and it produces an output and a new hidden state.
生成输出和新的隐藏状态
Back to our notebook. Here, I'm defining an RNN layer, self- doubt RNN.
回到 notebook在这里定义 RNN 层级 self.rnn
This RNN is taking in an input size and a hidden dimension
此 RNN 会接受 input_size 和 hidden_dim
that defines how many features the output of this RNN will have.
后者定义了此 RNN 的输出特征数量
Then it takes in a number of layers which allows you to create a stacked RNN if
然后是 n_layers 它使我们能够创建叠加 RNN
you want and this is typically a value kept between one and three layers.
通常设为 1 到 3 层
Finally, I'm setting batch first to true because I'm
最后 将 batch_first 设为 true
shaping the input such that the batch size will be the first dimension.
因为我将变形输入 使 batch_size 变成第一个维度
Okay. Then to complete this model I have to add
要完成此模型
one more layer which is a final fully-connected layer.
我需要再添加一层 即最终全连接层
This layer is responsible for producing the number of outputs,
此层级负责生成一定数量的输出
output size that I want given the output of the RNN.
数量等于我为此 RNN 设定的 output_size
So, all of these parameters are just going to be passed into our RNN when we create it.
在创建 RNN 时传入所有这些参数
You'll also note that I'm storing the value of
此外注意 我存储了 hidden_dim 的值
our hidden dimension so I can use it later in our forward function.
因为之后在 forward 函数中要使用它
In the forward function, I'm going to specify how a batch
我将在 forward 函数中
of input sequences will pass through this model.
指定一批输入序列如何经过此模型
Note that this forward takes in an input X and the hidden state.
注意 此 forward 接受输入 x 和隐藏状态
The first thing I'm doing is grabbing
首先我将通过调用 x.size(0)
the batch size of our input calling X dot size of 0.
获取输入的批次大小
Then I'm passing my initial input and hidden state into the RNN layer.
然后将初始输入和隐藏状态传入 RNN 层级
This produces the RNN output and a new hidden state.
生成 RNN 输出和新的隐藏状态
Then I'm going to call view on the RNN output to shape it into the size I want.
然后对 RNN 输出调用 view 以将其变形为我想要的形状
In this case that's going to be batch size, times sequence length
在此例中 行数将是批次大小乘以序列长度
rows and the hidden dimension number of columns.
列数将是隐藏维数
This is a flattening step where I'm
这是扁平化步骤
preparing the output to be fed into a fully-connected layer.
我们把输出准备好 然后传入全连接层
So, I'll pass this shaped output to the final fully-connected layer,
接着将此变形后的输出传入最终全连接层
and return my final output here and my hidden state generated from the RNN.
在这里返回最终输出和 RNN 生成的隐藏状态
Now, as a last step here,
最后一步
I'm going to actually create some text data and to
我将创建一些文本数据
test RNN and see if it's working as I expect.
测试 RNN 能否达到预期效果
The most common error I get when programming
编写 RNN 代码时我最常犯的错误是
RNNs is that I've messed up the data dimension somewhere.
在某个地方弄错数据维度
So, I'm just going to check that there as I expect.
因此我将检查下该 RNN 是否符合预期
So, here I'm just creating a test RNN with an input and output size of one,
在这里创建一个测试 RNN，输入和输出大小为 1
a hidden dimension of 10, and the number of layers equal to two,
隐藏维度为 10 层级数量等于 2
and you can change the hidden dimension and the number of layers.
你可以更改隐藏维度和层级数量
I basically just want to see that this is making the shape of outputs I expect.
我只是想检查是否能生成预期的形状
So, here I'm creating some test data that are sequence length along.
在这里创建一些测试数据 长度为 seq_length
I'm converting that data into a tensor datatype,
将该数据转换为张量
and I'm squeezing the first dimension to give it
压缩第一个维度
a batch size of one as a first dimension.
使其大小为 batch_size = 1
Then I'm going to print out this input size and I'll pass it into our test RNN as input.
然后输出此输入大小并将其传入测试 RNN 中
Recall that this takes an initial hidden state,
这个是初始隐藏状态
and an initial one here is just going to be none.
这里将设为 none
Then this should return an output and a hidden state,
它将返回输出和隐藏状态
and I'm going to print out those sizes as well.
同样输出这些大小
Okay. So, our input size is a 3D tensor which is exactly what I expect.
Ok输入大小是三维张量 和我预期的一样
If first dimension is one our batch size,
第一个维度是 1 即 batch_size
then 20 our sequence length,
序列长度是 20
and finally our input number of features.
最后是输入特征数量
Which is just one as we specified here.
也是 1 因为在这里指定为 1
The output size is a 2D tensor.
输出大小是二维张量
This is because in the forward function of our model definition actually
这是因为模型定义的 forward 函数
smooshed the batch size and sequence length into one parameter.
将批次大小和序列长度变成了一个参数
So, batch size times sequence length is 20 and then we have an output size of one.
因此批次大小乘以序列长度为 20 输出大小是 1
Finally we have our hidden state.
最后是隐藏状态
Now, the first dimension here is our number of
第一个维度值是 2
layers that I specified in the model definition two.
即在模型定义中指定的层数
Next we have the value one which is just the batch size of our input here.
第二个值是 1 表示输入的批次大小
Finally, the last dimension here is 10 which is just our hidden dimension.
最后一个维度值是 10 表示隐藏维度
So, all of these look pretty good and as I expect and I can proceed.
看起来不错 和我预期的一样
Next I'll show you how to train a model like this.
下面我将演示如何训练这样的模型